# Adegoke Akanbi

A Frontend Engineer with +3 years' experience helping companies and clients build elegant, scalable and reusable frontend interfaces. I fell in love with the magical powers of coding while collaborating (as a Counsel) with developers to create a digital solution. Now, I relish every moment writing code.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **78 Financial Solutions Ltd,** Nigeria — Frontend Engineer (Remote) **July 2021 - Present**

- I bridge the gap between graphic design and technical implementation by translating UI/UX design wireframes to reusable, scalable and well-commented code;
- I collaborate with back-end developers to integrate UI components with APIs and databases;
- I participate in code reviews and sprint meetings to ensure prompt delivery of web solutions. I also volunteered to be responsible for gathering information from end users about internal and external web applications for functionality and service improvements.
- I improved accessibility of the company's internal and public facing websites by incorporating WAI-ARIA specifications in web solutions.
   I also enhanced the company's online visibility by implementing SEO principles on the company's websites;
- I debug errors, troubleshoot issues, and perform routine performance optimizations on web applications.

# **Keystone Bank Ltd,** Nigeria — *Lead, Dispute Management* (Hybrid) **Nov 2018 - August 2022**

- Managed and resolved customer complaints to improve customer satisfaction and reduce adverse claims;
- Negotiated a dispute on behalf of the Bank saving over 2 billion naira in litigation claims against the Bank;
- Functioned as the legal IT support and Operational Risk Officer, responding to service issues and requests in respect of the dispute and vendor management portals in a timely manner;
- Provided onboarding training to new intakes to the Dispute Management Team.

# Access Bank Plc, Nigeria — Corporate Counsel (On-site) March 2013 - November 2018

- I developed a format for the Enterprise Risk Management Committee Report for the Legal Division, highlighting the summary of reports of disputes, resolutions and learning points to the Management/Board of the Bank.
- I trained Account Officers and Relationship Managers on credit/security documentations, regulatory and statutory requirements;
- I reviewed the Bank's litigation portfolio and recommended matters that should be settled out of court to the Bank's Management for settlement.

2492 Post Road
Unit 21, Oakville
Ontario, L6H 0K1
+1 (289) 818-3437
goke.akanbi@gmail.com
Github Profile
Portfolio Website

### **SKILLS**

JavaScript | jQuery | React.js |
Redux toolkit | Node.js |
MongoDB | Express.js |
Mongoose | NPM | NoSQL |
Wordpress | SQL | RESTful
API | Git | Github | Agile |
Webpack | Jest | Unit Testing |
SASS | Bootstrap | CSS3 |
HTML5

#### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

I was converted from Intern to Frontend Engineer within 2 months of internship with 78 Financials Ltd in recognition of my contribution to the Development Team.

I recommended dispute and vendor management systems that was implemented across all divisions in Keystone Bank to increase efficiency for all employees and reduce operational costs for the Bank.

I volunteered to serve as a member of the recruitment panel of Keystone Bank Ltd.

I mentored 5 direct reports as the Dispute Manager in Keystone Bank Ltd.

I was promoted within an appraisal year from a team member to team lead in Keystone Bank Ltd.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Scrimba.com** (Norway - Remote) Frontend Engineering

**Obafemi Awolowo University** Nigeria — Law Degree (LLB)